Finding Aid for Suomi College Finnish-American collection, 1880-1972
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Finnish-American Collection: Church Records, Labor Societies, Temperance Organizations, and others
  - Temperance Society Valon Leimu [The Flame of the Light], Rockport, Massachusetts
    - Minute books
      - February 16, 1947-September 4, 1957 (Reel 67)
    - Walotar (handwritten newspaper)
      - 1903-1905 (Reel 67)
      - 1906-1914 (Reel 67)
  - Temperance Society Valon Lähde [The Source of the Light], Eveleth, Minnesota
    - Minute book
      - 1895-1898 (Reel 67)
      - 1903-1905 (Reel 67)
      - October 8, 1905-June 23, 1906 (Reel 67)
      - June 29, 1906-December 28, 1906 (Reel 68)
      - January 6, 1907-November 13, 1910 (Reel 68)
      - November 20, 1910-January 30, 1933 (Reel 68)
  - Temperance Society Vesi [Water], Ely, Minnesota
    - Minute Books
      - July 1, 1894-August 13, 1898 (Reel 69)
      - September 8, 1901-September 4, 1904 (Reel 69)
      - September 11, 1904-May 2, 1909 (Reel 69)
      - May 2, 1909-September 9, 1912 (Reel 69)
      - September 15, 1912-July 30, 1913 (Reel 69)
      - August 17, 1913-September 26, 1915 (Reel 70)
      - December 18, 1923-August 17, 1931 (Reel 70)
      - August 31, 1931-January 7, 1935 (Reel 70)
      - March 22, 1943-October 18, 1948 (Reel 70)
      - November 1, 1948-January 7, 1955 (Reel 70)
      - February 4, 1955-May 25, 1960 (Reel 70)
    - Photographs (Reel 70)
  - Help Finland Materials (to help Finland during the Second World War)
    - Minute book
      - 1940-1941 (Portland, Oregon) (Reel 70)
    - Letters (Reel 70)
  - Industrial Workers of the World (IWW) Union (Virginia, Minnesota)
    - Minute book
      - January 3, 1929-June 2, 1931 (Reel 70)
  - The Finnish National Committee of De Kalb, Illinois
    - Minute book
      - 1926-1929
  - Temperance Society Aamurusko, [Glow], Negaunee, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - October 20, 1907-June 29, 1913 (Reel 71)
      - July 6, 1913-April 24, 1933 (Reel 71)
      - October 27, 1912-March 14, 1918 (room committee) (Reel 71)
  - Temperance Society [The Seed of Hope], Shafer, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - June 28, 1906-August 23, 1908 (Reel 71)
      - September 13, 1908-October 27, 1912 (Reel 71)
  - Finnish-Athletic Club Tarmo ja Huima [Energy and Hotspur] South Range, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - October 22, 1905-October 4, 1914 (Reel 71)
  - Temperance Society Urea, Tamarack Mills, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - November 14, 1915-July 7, 1918 (Reel 71)
  - Temperance Society Iltarusko [Sunset Glow], Trout Creek, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - June 30, 1895-April 25, 1909 (Reel 71)
  - Temperance Society Elo [Grain], Winona, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - July 6, 1909-July 7, 1918 (Reel 72)
  - Temperance Society Elon Toivo [The Hope of Life], Iron, Minnesota
    - Rules (Reel 72)
    - Minute book
      - February 2, 1936-January 10, 1944 (Reel 72)
      - 1933-March 2, 1952 (Reel 72)
  - Temperance Society Rannan Ruusu [The Rose of the Beach], Oskar, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - October 2, 1904-1905 (Reel 72)
      - November 7, 1909-January 28, 1917 (Reel 72)
  - Help Finland Materials (to help Finland during the Second World War)
    - Accounts (Reel 72)
  - Temperance Society Kyntäjä [Plowman], Copper Range, Mich.
    - Minute book
      - December 30, 1900-October 12, 1902 (Reel 73)
    - Rules (Reel 73)
    - Minute book
      - February 24, 1906-February 21, 1909 (Reel 73)
      - February 28, 1909-July 9, 1910 (Reel 73)
      - July 10, 1909-May 2, 1918 (Reel 73)
  - Temperance Society Taimi [Plant], Palmer, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - 1894-1901 (Reel 73)
      - 1901-1915 (Reel 73)
      - 1915-1948 (Reel 73)
  - Temperance Society Valkoruusu [White Rose], Rockland, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - November 15, 1903-December 1, 1907 (Reel 74)
      - December 8, 1907-March 26, 1911 (Reel 74)
  - Temperance Society Toivola, Crystal Falls, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - July 2, 1943-November 13, 1958 (Reel 74)
      - January 18, 1891-January 29, 1893 (Reel 74)
      - February 26, 1893-June 10, 1894 (Reel 74)
      - June 17, 1894-April 21, 1895 (Reel 74)
      - September 4, 1904-June 23, 1907 (Reel 75)
      - June 30, 1907-June 7, 1915 (Reel 75)
      - July 28, 1915-May 19, 1943 (Reel 75)
  - Temperance Society Korven Kukka [The Flower of the Wilderness], Amasa, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - October 6, 1901-June 15, 1913 (Reel 75)
      - January 1, 1936-January 23, 1945 (Reel 76)
  - Temperance Society Väinötär. National Mine, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - May 31, 1896-September 20, 1903 (Reel 76)
  - Finnish Illness and Accident Aid Association (Hancock, Michigan)
    - Minute books
      - January 14, 1911-March 8, 1924 (Reel 76)
      - April 12, 1924-April 12, 1942 (Reel 76)
      - May 10, 1942-June 8, 1965 (Reel 76)
      - March 27, 1892-August 13, 1904 (Reel 76)
      - September 10, 1904-December 10, 1910 (Reel 76)
  - Help Finland Committee of Troy, New Hampshire
    - Minute book
      - December 10, 1939-January 4, 1944 (Reel 77)
  - Finnish Workers' Association of Maynard, Massachusetts
    - Minute books
      - January 13, 1907-December 12, 1909 (official meetings) (Reel 77)
      - January 22, 1909-June 4, 1914 (board of directors) (Reel 77)
      - September 28, 1913-July 23, 1916 (official meetings) (Reel 77)
      - August 6, 1916-November 12, 1916 (official meetings) (Reel 78)
      - November 26, 1916-October 26, 1919 (official meetings) (Reel 78)
      - May 9, 1917-July 10, 1919 (board of directors) (Reel 78)
      - 1918-1929 (annual meeting) (Reel 78)
      - July 17, 1919-November 5, 1925 (board of directors) (Reel 78)
      - February 16, 1921-January 25, 1932 (board of directors) (Reel 79)
      - January 20, 1920-January 30, 1924 (agitation committee) (Reel 79)
      - September 28, 1936-January 23, 1939 (official meetings) (Reel 79)
      - February 6, 1939-May 27, 1940 (Reel 79)
    - Membership book (Reel 79)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Maynard, Massachusetts
    - Membership book (Reel 79)
    - Baptisms 1913-1963 (Reel 79)
    - Confirmations 1914-1962 (Reel 79)
    - Reception of members 1952-1962 (Reel 79)
    - Dismissal of members 1953-1962 (Reel 79)
    - Funerals 1914-1962 (Reel 79)
    - Minute books
      - May 5, 1909-May 10, 1925 (official meetings) (Reel 79)
      - July 22, 1925-October 13, 1931 (official meetings) (Reel 80)
      - January 1, 1929-April 14, 1931 (official meetings) (Reel 80)
      - November 8, 1931-October 21, 1962 (official meetings) (Reel 80)
      - October 5, 1927-March 9, 1932 (sewing circle) (Reel 80)
      - February 25, 1920-October 1, 1925 (sewing circle) (Reel 80)
    - Membership book (Reel 80)
    - Membership book (Reel 80)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of West Barnstable, Mass.
    - Membership book No. 1 (started in 1915) (Reel 81)
    - Membership book No. 2 (Reel 81)
    - Baptisms 1930-1956 (Reel 81)
    - Confirmations 1931-1953 (Reel 81)
    - Marriages 1930-1955 (Reel 81)
    - Funerals 1931-1956 (Reel 81)
    - Minute books
      - January 18, 1915-January 12, 1958 (official meetings) (Reel 81)
      - April 7, 1930-April 2, 1936 (Luther League) (Reel 81)
      - April 11, 1956-June 5, 1959 (board of directors) (Reel 81)
      - May 1, 1940-October 5, 1948 (sewing circle) (Reel 81)
      - May 9, 1952-February 15, 1965 (altar guild) (Reel 81)
    - Pastor's notebooks: Baptisms, Confirmations, Marriages, and Funerals, 2 items (Reel 81)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Hyannis, Massachusetts
    - Membership book (Reel 81)
  - Finnish Workers' Association of Quincy, Massachusetts
    - Minute books (official meetings)
      - February 12, 1939-March 10, 1955 (Reel 82)
      - April 14, 1955-May 8, 1968 (Reel 82)
      - October 28, 1903-September 25, 1907 (Reel 82)
      - April 5, 1905-November 9, 1913 (Reel 82)
      - December 7, 1913-January 5, 1919 (Reel 82)
      - January 19, 1919-May 8, 1921 (Reel 83)
      - May 15, 1918-January 16, 1968 (Reel 83)
      - May 22, 1921-March 16, 1924 (Reel 83)
      - November 3, 1929-January 8, 1939 (Reel 83)
    - Minute Books (board of directors)
      - October 1, 1907-November 15, 1910 (Reel 83)
      - November 22, 1910-November 3, 1915 (Reel 84)
      - November 9, 1915-November 17, 1922 (Reel 84)
      - October 14, 1930-May 10, 1932 (Reel 84)
      - May 17, 1932-January 9, 1934 (Reel 85)
      - January 26, 1937-December 10, 1940 (Reel 85)
      - January 6, 1943-July 3, 1957 (Reel 85)
      - December 4, 1957-March 3, 1965 (Reel 85)
      - April 7, 1965-October 13, 1968 (Reel 85)
    - Minute Book (relief association)
      - January 1, 1907-November 30, 1913 (Reel 85)
    - Wäittäjä [Debater] (handwritten newspaper)
      - 1910-1911 (Reel 85)
      - 1914 (Reel 85)
      - 1914-1915 (Reel 86)
      - 1916-1917 (Reel 86)
      - 1918-1919 (Reel 86)
      - 1921-1923 (Reel 86)
    - Minute books (entertainment committee)
      - November 26, 1903-December 10, 1906 (Reel 86)
      - December 15, 1906-April 10, 1908 (Reel 86)
  - Temperance Society Huvitus [Amusement], Baraga, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - February 1, 1892-February 25, 1894 (Reel 87)
  - Temperance Society Auran Kukka [The Flower of Aura], Baltic Mine, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - December 9, 1900-November 29, 1903 (Reel 87)
  - Temperance Society Onnen Kukka [The Flower of Happiness], Chassell, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - March 21, 1909-December 13, 1914 (Reel 87)
  - Temperance Society Kyntää [Plowman], Covington, Michigan
    - Rules (Reel 87)
    - Cash book 1913 (Reel 87)
    - Minute book
      - February 16, 1913-March 29, 1918 (Reel 87)
    - Cash book 1914-1915 (Reel 87)
    - Minute book
      - May 5, 1918-April 29, 1957 (Reel 87)
    - Cash books 1920s, 1930s (Reel 87)
  - Temperance Society Sovittaja [Mediator], Worcester, Massachusetts
    - Minute books
      - April 6, 1890-October 11, 1896 (Reel 87)
      - June 9, 1901-July 5, 1903 (Reel 88)
      - July 12, 1903-May 20, 1906 (Reel 88)
      - May 27, 1906-October 29, 1911 (Reel 88)
      - November 12, 1911-May 12, 1912 (Reel 88)
      - December 19, 1910-December 14, 1913 (Reel 89)
      - December 21, 1913-August 9, 1914 (Reel 89)
      - August 23, 1914-March 18, 1917 (Reel 89)
      - March 25, 1917-January 11, 1920 (Reel 89)
      - January 18, 1920-April 11, 1920 (Reel 90)
      - April 18, 1920-October 22, 1922 (Reel 90)
      - October 29, 1922-December 27, 1925 (Reel 90)
      - January 3, 1926-November 8, 1931 (Reel 90)
      - November 29, 1931-October 1, 1939 (Reel 90)
      - November 5, 1939-February 10, 1946 (Reel 90)
      - September 17, 1933-February 5, 1939 (board of directors) (Reel 91)
      - January 7, 1940-November 21, 1954 (board of directors) (Reel 91)
      - December 12, 1942-January 1, 1949 (sewing circle) (Reel 91)
      - February 19, 1922-April 27, 1923 (young people's club) (Reel 91)
  - Temperance Society Sivuttaja [Passer], Waukegan, Illinois
    - Minute book
      - April 14, 1901-September 25, 1904 (Reel 91)
      - October 2, 1904-1907 (Reel 91)
      - October 30, 1910-September 21, 1913 (Reel 91)
      - August 13, 1934-January 30, 1944 (board of directors) (Reel 92)
      - September 7, 1913-May 6, 1917 (entertainment comm. (Reel 92)
      - July 15, 1899-March 31, 1901 (Reel 92)
    - Rules (Reel 92)
    - Minute book
      - September 25, 1913-October 17, 1915 (Reel 92)
      - October 28, 1915-July 27, 1919 (Reel 92)
      - August 17, 1919-December 29, 1923 (Reel 92)
      - January 5, 1924-June 28, 1931 (Reel 92)
      - August 9, 1931-November 16, 1941 (Reel 92)
      - December 21, 1941-June 13, 1954 (Reel 93)
      - April 29, 1900-December 18, 1904 (young people's club) (Reel 93)
      - May 1, 1905-February 13, 1908 (young people's club) (Reel 93)
      - August 31, 1911-March 25, 1914 (sewing circle) (Reel 93)
      - April 9, 1914-October 12, 1922 (sewing circle) (Reel 93)
      - November 9, 1922-March 24, 1929 (sewing circle) (Reel 93)
      - April 21, 1929-January 14, 1939 (sewing circle) (Reel 93)
      - February 5, 1939-December 14, 1944 (sewing circle) (Reel 93)
      - January 1945-October 11, 1962 (sewing circle) (Reel 93)
  - Suomalais-Kansallis-Raittius-Weljeysseuran (SKRW) arkisto [The Archive Finnish-National-Temperance-Brotherhood], the top organization of the Finnish-American temperance societies
    - Minute books
      - September 14, 1912-July 29, 1916 (Reel 94)
      - July 30, 1916-July 9, 1919 (Reel 94)
      - July 10, 1919-April 29, 1926 (Reel 94)
      - June 13, 1926-January 7, 1933 (Reel 94)
      - June 3, 1933-June 6, 1948 (Reel 94)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Hancock, Michigan
    - Marriages (Reel 95)
    - Funerals (Reel 95)
    - Baptisms 1887-1889 (Reel 95)
    - Confirmations 1889-1891 (Reel 95)
    - Marriages 1888-1894 (Reel 95)
    - Baptisms 1889-1894 (Reel 95)
    - Baptisms 1894-1901 (Reel 95)
    - Annual report of the minister 1912-1936 (Reel 95)
    - Baptisms 1912-1914 (Reel 95)
    - Minute books (church council)
      - February 8, 1917-August 10, 1925 (Reel 95)
      - August 23, 1925-December 2, 1935 (Reel 95)
      - January 5, 1936-January 7, 1945 (Reel 95)
      - May 1, 1910-July 12, 1926 (Reel 96)
      - December 1, 1941-February 3, 1969 (Reel 96)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Markham, Minnesota
    - Membership book (Reel 96)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Virginia, Minnesota
    - Minute book
      - June 29, 1925-January 5, 1947 (Reel 96)
  - Kansanvalistusseura [Popular Educational Society], Calumet, Michigan
    - Rules (Reel 97)
    - Minute book
      - May 26, 1883-November 10, 1918 (Reel 97)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Aitkin, Minnesota
    - Membership book (Reel 97)
    - Minute book
      - August 15, 1943-August 2, 1966 (Reel 97)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Middle River, Minnesota
    - Membership book (Reel 97)
    - Minute book
      - August 15, 1943-August 2, 1966 (Reel 97)
  - Finnish Lutheran Congregation of Monessen, Pennsylvania
    - Minute book
      - September 10, 1899-April 20, 1917 (Reel 97)
    - A brief history of the church (Reel 97)
    - The Story of the Finnish Community in Monessen, Pennsylvania (manuscript, in English) (Reel 97)
  - Finnish Workers' Association of Maple Ridge
    - A brief history of the association (Reel 97)
  - Materials on Suomi College, Hancock, Michigan
    - Minute book (temperance club)
      - October 20, 1906-January 31, 1914 (Reel 97)
      - February 14, 1914-May 25, 1920 (Reel 97)
    - Rules of the students' organization (Reel 97)
    - Minute book (students' organization)
      - February 27, 1915-October 28, 1922 (Reel 97)
  - The Archives of Suomi Synod (the top organization of the Finnish Lutheran congregations)
    - Rules (Minnesota Conference) (Reel 98)
    - Minute books
      - May 25, 1929-February 3, 1942 (Minnesota Conference) (Reel 98)
      - June 6, 1942-December 9, 1962 (Minnesota Conference) (Reel 98)
      - 1889-1904 (the Consistory of Suomi Synod) (Reel 98)
      - December 17, 1889-June 26, 1919 (the Consistory of Suomi Synod) (Reel 98)
      - July 15, 1919-February 3, 1925 (the Consistory of Suomi Synod) (Reel 98)
      - June 9, 1915-June 12, 1926 (Church Assembly) (Reel 98)
      - June 9, 1927-June 14, 1950 (Church Assembly) (Reel 99)
      - August 20, 1909-April 15, 1928 (Western Conference) (Reel 99)
      - September 9, 1910-February 24, 1936 (board of directors of Western Conference and Columbia Conference) (Reel 99)
      - April 18, 1936-May 1, 1955 (Columbia Conference) (Reel 99)
      - January 29, 1912-April 28, 1945 (Michigan Conference) (Reel 99)
    - Letters (Reel 99)
  - Finnish Congregational Church of West Paris, Maine
    - Baptisms 1914-1937 (Reel 100)
    - Confirmations 1917-1926 (Reel 100)
    - Marriages 1915-1926 (Reel 100)
    - Funerals 1917-1946 (Reel 100)
    - Baptisms 1910-1914 (Reel 100)
    - Marriages 1910-1914 (Reel 100)
    - Minute book
      - 1907 (Reel 100)
    - Letters (Reel 100)
    - Photographs (Reel 100)
    - Minute books
      - June 9, 1912-July 23, 1916 (Reel 100)
      - August 29, 1926-September 27, 1942 (Reel 100)
      - October 25, 1942-November 30, 1952 (Reel 100)
      - January 4, 1953-January March 1960 (Reel 100)
      - January 31, 1960-October 27, 1968 (Reel 100)
      - January 6, 1920-January 8, 1939 (Sunday school) (Reel 100)
  - Finnish Congregational Church of Harrison, Maine
    - Minute books
      - January 6, 1920-August 21, 1932 (Reel 100)
      - 1920-1935 (Reel 100)
  - Finnish Lutheran Publishing Company (Hancock, Michigan)
    - Minute book
      - July 6, 1932-December 7, 1938 (Reel 100)
  - Temperance Society Nuorison Kaunistus [The Beauty of the Youth], Redridge, Michigan
    - Minute book
      - November 6, 1904-February 4, 1906 (Reel 100)
Subject Index to Microfilm
This index was prepared from the original container listing. As the materials were microfilmed in a somewhat random order, this index intends to bring together church, temperance, labor, and other organizational records. In this index, the records are further listed alphabetically and then by place name.
Church Records:
The Archives of Suomi Synod (the top organization of the Finnish Lutheran congregations), Reels 98 and 99
Eastern Conference of Suomi Synod Lutheran Guild, Reel 43
The Families of the ministers in the Eastern Section of Suomi Synod, Reel 63
Finnish Congregational Churches
Maine
Harrison, Maine, Reel 100
West Paris, Maine, Reel 100
Massachusetts
Maynard, Mass., Reels 48 and 49
New Hampshire
Troy, N.H., Reels 52 and 53
Finnish Lutheran Congregations
Canada, Ontario
Cobalt, Ontario, Canada, Reel 62
Ohio
Girard, Ohio, Reel 32
Illinois
Waukegan, Illinois, Reel 26-30
Massachusetts
Gardner, Mass., Reel 48
Hyannis, Mass., Reel 81
Maynard, Mass., Reels 79 and 80
West Barnstable, Mass., Reel 81
Worcester, Mass., Reels 45-48
Michigan
Amasa, Mich., Reel 7
Covington, Mich., Reel 7
Crystal Falls, Mich., Reels 5 and 6
Elo, Mich., Reel 13
Gwinn, Mich., Reel 9
Hancock, Mich., Reels 95 and 96
Ironwood, Mich., Reels 18 and 19
L'Anse, Mich., Reel 8
Laird, Mich., Reels 12 and 13
Munising, Mich., Reels 9 and 10
National Mine [Winthrop], Mich., Reel 8
Newberry, Mich., Reels 10 and 11
Nisula, Mich., Reel 13
Palmer, Mich., Reel 8
Pelkie (Kyrö), Mich., Reels 13 and 14
Pequaming, Mich., Reel 7
Princeton, Mich., Reel 9
Ramsay, Mich., Reel 18
Sault Ste. Marie, Mich., Reel 12
Stambaugh, Mich., Reel 7
Uusi Suomi [New Finland], Mich., Reel 8
Wakefield, Mich., Reels 17 and 18
Minnesota
Aitkin, Minnesota, Reel 97
Markham, Minnesota, Reel 96
Middle River, Minnesota, Reel 97
Virginia, Minnesota, Reel 65 and 96
Pennsylvania
Glassport, Penn., Reel 56
Monessen, Penn., Reel 97
Nanty Glo, Penn., Reels 32 and 33
New Castle, Penn., Reel 34
Rankin, Penn., Reel 34
Walston, Penn., Reel 34
Wisconsin
Iron Belt, Wisc., Reel 18 and 36
Marengo, Wisc., Reel 18
Montreal, Wisc., Reel 18
Unknown State
Cave Hill, Reel 63
Finnish National Lutheran Congregation of Ironwood, Mich, Reels 14-17
Swedish-Finnish Congregations
Michigan
Grand Marais, Mich., Reel 9
Newberry, Mich., Reel 10
Sault Ste. Marie, Mich., Reel 12
Swedish-Finnish Lutheran Congregations
Michigan
Amasa, Mich., Reel 7
Crystal Falls, Mich., Reel 6
Metropolitan, Mich., Reel 5
Munising, Mich., Reel 10
Norway, Mich., Reel 4
Labor Organizations
Finnish Workers' Associations
Massachusetts
Maynard, Mass., Reels 77-79
Quincy, Mass., Reels 82-86
Worcester, Mass., Reels 44 and 45
Minnesota
Cloquet, Minnesota, Reel 31
New Hampshire
Newport, N.H., Reel 49-52
Unknown State
Maple Ridge, Reel 97
The Finnish Workers' Illness and Funeral Aid Organization, Monessen, Penn., Reels 58-60
Industrial Workers of the World (IWW) Union (Virginia, Minnesota), Reel 70
Temperance Societies:
Suomalais-Kansallis-Raittius-Weljeysseuran (SKRW) arkisto [The Archive Finnish-National-Temperance-Brotherhood], the top organization of the Finnish-American temperance societies, Reel 94
Illinois
Sivuttaja [Passer], Waukegan, Illinois, Reels 91-93
Temperance League of Illinois, Reel 33
Maine
Riento [Active], Monson, Maine, Reel 42
Massachusetts
Alku [Beginning], Maynard, Mass., Reels 39-42
Sovittaja [Mediator], Worcester, Mass., Reels 87-91
Valon Leimu [The Flame of the Light], Rockport, Mass., Reels 66 and 67
Michigan
Aamurusko, [Glow], Negaunee, Mich., Reel 71
Apilan Kukka [Blossom of Clover], Rudyard, Mich., Reel 43
Auran Kukka [The Flower of Aura], Baltic Mine, Mich., Reel 87
Elo [Grain], Winona, Mich., Reel 72
Huvitus [Amusement], Baraga, Mich., Reel 87
Hyvä Toivo [Good Hope], Calumet, Mich., Reel 12
Iltarusko [Sunset Glow], Trout Creek, Mich., Reel 71
Korven Kukka [The Flower of the Wilderness], Amasa, Mich., Reels 75 and 76
Kyntäjä [Plowman], Copper Range, Mich., Reel 73
Kyntää [Plowman], Covington, Mich., Reel 87
Nuorison Kaunistus [The Beauty of the Youth], Redridge, Mich., Reel 100
Onnela [Place of Happiness], Iron Mountain, Mich., Reel 33
Onnen Aarre [The Treasure of Happiness], Newberry, Mich., Reel 10
Onnen Kukka [The Flower of Happiness], Chassell, Mich., Reel 87
Onnen Satama [Harbor of Happiness], Covington, Mich., Reel 43
Rannan Ruusu [The Rose of the Beach], Oskar, Mich., Reel 72
Roihu [Flame], Coburntown, Mich., Reels 42 and 43
Taimi [Plant], Palmer, Mich., Reel 73
[The Seed of Hope], Shafer, Mich., Reel 71
Temperance League of Iron County, Mich., Reel 33
Temperance League of Marquette County, Mich., Reel 33
Toivo [Hope], Wakefield, Mich., Reel 53
Toivola [Place of Hope], Crystal Falls, Mich., Reels 74 and 75
Urpa, Tamarack Mills, Mich., Reel 71
Valkoruusu [White Rose], Rockland, Mich., Reel 74
Väinötär, National Mine, Mich., Reel 76
Minnesota
Elon Toivo [The Hope of Life], Iron, Minnesota, Reel 72
Ilmarinen, Cloquet, Minnesota, Reel 33
Pohjan Leimu [The Flame of the North], Soudan, Minnesota, Reels 64 and 65
Rantakorven Kukka [The Flower of the Wilderness Beach], Buhl, Minnesota, Reel 65
Toivon Tähti [The Star of Hope], Duluth, Minnesota, Reel 33
Valon Lähde [The Source of the Light], Eveleth, Minnesota, Reels 67 and 68
Vesi [Water], Ely, Minnesota, Reels 69 and 70
New Hampshire
Onnen Koitto [The Dawn of Happiness], West Concord, N.H., Reel 34
New York
Tähti [Star], New York, N.Y., Reels 57 and 58
Ohio
Hedelmä [Fruit], Warren, Ohio, Reels 21 and 22
Hyvä Tahto [Good Will], Ashtabula Harbor, Ohio, Reel 20
Kasvi [Plant], Fairport Harbor, Ohio, Reels 36-38
Kunto [Condition], Ashtabula, Ohio, Reel 20 and 21
Sovinto [Harmony], Ashtabula, Ohio, Reel 20
Suomen Ruusu [The Rose of Finland], Cleveland and Ashtabula, Ohio, Reels 1,2, 20, and 56
Toivon Alku [Beginning of the Hope], Girard, Ohio, Reel 22
Toivon Sankari [The Hero of the Hope], Youngstown, Ohio, Reels 2 and 3
Uuudenvuoden Lahja [The Gift of the New Year], Lowellville, Ohio, Reel 3
Oregon
Suomi [Finland], Astoria, Oregon, Reel 38
Pennsylvania
Laakson Ruusu [The Rose of the Valley], Ansonville, Penn., Reel 22
Pyrintö [Aspiration], Coal Centers, Penn., Reel 32
Rauhan Alku [The Beginning of Peace], Monessen, Penn., Reel 32
Toivon Liitto [The Alliance of Hope], Monessen, Penn., Reel 34
Uusi Toivo [New Hope], New Castle, Penn., Reel 35
Vesa [Sprout], Glassport, Penn., Reels 56 and 57
Voiton Lippu [The Flag of Victory], Monessen, Penn., Reels 32, 34, 60, and 61
West Virginia
Elämän Toivo [The Hope of Life], Weirton, West Virginia, Reel 63
Tähti [Star], Clarksburg, West Virginia, Reel 63
Wisconsin
Kalevan Miekka [The Sword of Kaleva], Montreal, Wisc., Reel 35
Other Organizations
The Accident, Illness and Burial Relief Society of Monessen, Penn., Reel 3
The Archive of the Finnish-American Historical Society of Mich. (Detroit, Mich.), Reel 23
The Archive of the Historical Museum in Kaleva, Mich., Reels 23-26